so epifanio's true paleo game let's play
a game so would you like to start would
you like to show a little bit about what
we've been working on here okay so a
very brief introduction to this notion
called monarchy the monarchy is
basically a hierarchy which max out a
relationship between the two polarities
in that hierarchy namely the monarch and
the an arc and the interior of the
pyramid shows a sort of ascending
complexification of skill and capacity
and attainment leading to a transcendent
moment where connection between top and
bottom is realized and so that that's
that's a very very brief overall look so
the four domains are at the base direct
experience which is exactly as it says I
mean no explanation is really required
for that moving up to information where
that direct sensory experience begins to
be categorized and analyzed and
characterized and preference is shown
and this kind of thing the third domain
of knowledge is again a synthesis of
that information into useful employments
of that information and so again it's
about cross-referencing it's about
recording it's about teaching and
learning it's about passing knowledge
down that kind of thing and then finally
at the top is the notion of wisdom which
is the final integration of all of the
knowledge and all of the information and
all of the experience you have into the
making of optimal decisions and then
those optimal decisions in form right
down at the bottom again the quality of
the experience that you can extract from
the world and and so on and so on and so
on and the idea is that this basic map
applies all scales so it applies within
the individual
it applies within you know a
relationship of a few individuals to
each other into the broader community
inter into the world at large ultimately
and I think that's probably enough for
me to say as a basic introduction
oops the monarchy the monarch the an arc
and the synergy of the two the monarch
at the summit the Nexus of sovereignty
the Nexus of the decision-making the an
arc at the bottom the myriad explorers
the myriad pores of the membrane through
which experience seeps in experience
seeping in through the porous and Markel
membrane and then flowing inwards
towards the core where the monarch
resides the monarch integrates the
information and selects decides between
alternating timelines that will benefit
the Minar the man Aniki the most
increasing scope capacity sovereignty
wisdom constraint abstraction as we go
up the hierarchy of the hierarchy we
encounter more and more decision-making
power although the decision-making power
isn't concentrated in the monarch but it
is validated by the sovereign core but
on the way up and on the way down the
various degrees of sense making of
meaning making of taking decisions
according to the amount of information
that lies at that specific level
so we're always oscillating between
these positions between the position of
the monarch and the position of the anak
and we're trying to cultivate our
sovereignty and we're trying to
cultivate our agency our sovereignty in
the monarch and our agency in the Anarch
we're cultivating the core of our being
where the fundamental laws of our life
lies and we're cultivating the agency
our capability to further explore the
environment in novel ways
the notion of the constant feedback
between the monarch and the an art that
they are in a sense the same thing that
very much two sides of the same coin and
so within each of the four domains in
the direct experience domain there's
there's raw feelings but sensing is
about attention and so attention is a
form of sovereignty over your feelings
that choosing where to direct you to
choosing which feelings to focus your
attention on there and MMS is where the
sensory input is focus this is the
relevance realization in the information
section you know exploring is is is a
pretty free and open process there's no
boundaries to it but the process of
mapping then informs exploring it makes
the exploring selective what's relevant
what's important what's necessary in the
knowledge section the learning and
relating so learning is having absorbed
information and internalized information
but until you start relating they're
internalized information with other
internalized information and with
information of the outside world and how
to act in their outside world and
feedback from other people and so on
this deepens the knowledge and and and
this opens the door to the possibility
of wisdom when you have completely
integrated this the the the monarch and
anak and the monarch and and it through
all of these iterations as you work your
way up you are now finally only now
finally capable of making effective wise
decisions which not only serve oneself
in the moment but also serve the entire
mentality by broadening the possibility
of experience that can be had right back
down at the bottom of the an arc again
the monarch the sovereign the anak the
agent the integration of the hierarchy
on all levels guides us to the good life
the individual who has integrated the
brain stem to the neocortex weaving all
the different levels together of having
a healthy deep breath at the bottom and
the greatest sensitivity to the world at
the top integrating the hierarchy in
society giving the anak the direct
connection to the monarch and the
capability to influence the Monarchs
decision so the monarch has an extremely
high-resolution informational source in
an ANA which is integrated into the
Monarchs informational processing
capabilities the monarch representing in
embodied form in the form of actual
human beings in the form of a royal
family a royal tribe that is not defined
by bloodlines but is defined by
democracy by a competition of who can be
the best symbolic representation of the
divine here on earth who can maintain
such perfect toys that they can
participate in divine rituals that bind
the whole population together how can we
create a processing capability of the
monarch maybe in the form of artificial
intelligence who is capable of taking
the decisions that we need to create a
better world in a world in an era of
increasing complexity patient so there
is no one individual who could be
sufficiently educated to take the
decisions necessary to prevent the
collapse of civilization and to lead us
into a greater future
there's not even a family or a group of
people there's no clique of intelligence
that is capable eyes own to produce this
level of decision-making so what is
needed what is needed is a monarch that
cinta grates the best of artificial
intelligence and the best of collective
intelligence a monarch which has access
to as much information as possible can
integrate that information into making
decisions but it's always tempered by a
human soul by human collective
intelligence who can help guide this AI
towards making decisions that will not
only benefit the monarch but will
benefit the an arc and the monarchy as a
whole the monarchy as a whole is is an
expression of balance above and beyond
anything else
it seems worth mentioning looking at
exploring what happens if one dominates
the other if they if they get out of
balance with each other if one dominates
the other and this is clearly a massive
oversimplification but again looking at
each of these four domains if sensing
dominates feeling so if a monarch
dominates the an arc in this balance in
this in this interplay being this dance
between the two poles if that healthy
dance is interrupted and sensing for
example dominates feeling then what you
or your ex your expectations of the
world diamond
your ability to actually be in the world
if the feeling dominates the sensing
you're overwhelmed all the time you
can't you can't put anything in any kind
of order you're overwhelmed all the time
and so the the interplay the balance
between these two things the constant
dynamic interplay between at every level
and at every scale is that is is is the
really crucial essence of this I mean
again moving up another one mapping and
exploring this is the now becoming
almost a cliche phrase of you know don't
confuse the map with the territory if
you if you get fixated on the map you
are not capable of exploring you're not
capable of seeing the territory for what
it is equally if you don't map the
turrets you end up exploring the same
thing over and over and over again being
unable to learn and retain anything from
it being unable to abstract and
therefore being unable to expand the
territory that you can explore and so on
and so on but I think that the the
notion of maintaining the balance
between the monarch in the an arc is a
crucial thing to hold
primary at all times the flow of energy
between the unyk and the monarch the
Anna collects the resources sends them
up to the monarch the monarch to decide
how should the resources be distributed
so the annex ends up the resources and
the monarch has mapped where is no
surface where is there a deficit and can
rebalance the distribution of resources
in the hierarchy so is that the an arc
could be in the best possible health and
the monarch can be in the best possible
health this is a ritual this is a ritual
of redistribution that can be performed
by actual people where one Falls
together resources they an ark and all
the levels in in-between and give their
excess and those who are in need come to
the same place and the monarch can
redistribute in symbolic form but also
in concrete redistribution to the people
who are in need and beyond that the
monarch can represent divine principles
such as chance and fate and in these
rituals people can receive some of the
surplus by chance just like one is born
by chance into a specific family into a
specific position in the hierarchy this
regular ritual would reproduce that
dynamic and maybe by chance in this year
of the turn of the globe you will be
lucky enough to receive a gift from the
gods which is a prize
of some sort a surprise of some sort
this year instead of living the way that
you have lived you will live the next
year with a plane ticket to wherever you
want one year round you can go and
explore or the globe and you've received
this not quite any merit just by the
pure chance just like others have
received things by no merit but just by
the pure chance of their birth you to
have the possibility the benefit from
the chance of the gods
so the Molalla key aims to rear it
relies society in a way that links the
monarchy and the anarchy of generating
new ways of representing in symbolic
form the importance of the monarch and
the importance of the unlock so one
question would be what kind of symbolic
embodiments could be created for the the
notion of honouring and embodying this
balance and interplay through ritual and
ceremony feels super important I mean
such things already exists right
coronations of kings and queens you know
the the an arc comes out in their
Millions to honor the you know to honor
the mana and the monarch bestows their
blessing in exchange I mean III know
this sounds to the modern ear this kind
of thing can sound very silly and
out-of-date but the archetype of the
king and the blessing of the king create
fertility and prosperity and happiness
and and so on in the kingdom I mean it's
it's it's a very ancient and archetypal
notion and the loss of these rituals and
also that the loss of ritual worth
coming back to but the blockage that
exists currently in the world where
everything gets gets channeled up to the
monarch but then the blessing of the
monarch is not is not fully bestowed yet
the the the the cycle is not properly
completed a lot of it gets jammed up
there the resources in in in the
broadest sense of the world not in word
not just stuff but the the energy the
creativity the devotion and and so on
the attention I guess above all else is
is not redirected and reach annulled so
the King archetype is the embodiment of
strength and wisdom but also compassion
and is a is a is a force of generation
and driving forward and enrichment of
all is is at the heart of the is at the
heart of the monarch some slightly
jumbled and random not random but
slightly jumbled and not particularly
well articulated thoughts there the
monarch as the representations on earth
of the Divine Mother and the divine
father and the Anna as the
representation of the divine child the
an arc we use the society through its
explorations through its collection of
resources and the monarch taps into the
ancient wisdoms ancient traditions
best mate be wise wise decisions
necessary to guide a society the flow of
resources currently goes upwards towards
higher levels of the hierarchy and does
not get distributed back down and this
is what is preventing the flourishing of
society the society flourishes when
there is sufficient resources but can
flow throughout the system in a way that
maintains all parts of the hierarchy -
at the minimum the foundation of
survival
so the
players can relax and thereby perform
their tasks to their fullest function
rather than fighting within themselves
and amongst themselves because of the
amount of stress and anxiety that they
have within their bodies right now what
is happening is the sovereignty of the
an arc is being hijacked by the monarch
the sovereignty of the an arc to make
decisions but belong to them and do not
belong to others is taken away by the
monarch because the monarch currently is
guiding be an ark even manipulating an
arc through the use of symbols in the
use of false scarcity to perform its
will not the will of the monarchy of the
will of the monarchy
not the will of the totality but the
will of apart which is pretending to be
the totality creating a set of affairs
creating an an image of circumstances
that gives the appearance of this is the
way that things should be this is the
way the things have to be there is no
better hierarchy than the one that
currently exists this is the inevitable
hierarchy but this is a false dream this
is a false dream woven by that dream
weavers we're trying to maintain the
hierarchy in a shape that benefits them
the most and that is the shape of the
Terra mind that is the shape of
imprinting a pyramid in the mind as the
just hierarchy but the image of the
banana key is
elusive because there's another half to
this image the other half is the same
triangle flipped and placed at the top
the two tips connecting which represents
the flow of the resources up from the a
lock to the monarch continuing back up
to the an RB N and then another triangle
on top the resources flow again to the
monarch and then continue upwards to the
L R and this is the spiraling upwards of
social evolution
it's analogous to a form of distillation
right the the processing of experience
through the various layers of refinement
to the final attainment of wisdom and
making of good decisions is a
distillation into lower and lower
resolution but more and more and more
powerful like compression layer like
putting it into a zip folder is it's
smaller and more portable but at the
same time an end lower resolution but at
the same time far more capable and and
and then that distillation is passed on
to the next cycle of the turn so you
know and and and that's the beginning of
the next one and then and further
distillation and a further distillation
and the expulsion of that which is not
necessary and not relevant the breaking
and reforming of that which is right
that which is needed that which is that
which is good if if if you will is is
part of this oscillation which is
created with the triangles alternating
base to base tip to tip on top of each
other creates a sense of oscillation the
monarch represents the prize giver and
the reestablishment of the new
playground at the beginning and end of
each turn at the end of the turn the
monarch distributes the prizes to the
various players the fact that
rice comes from the monarch is
symbolically important because it
reproduces our relationship to our
parents but this time our relationship
to the divine parents and they reward
the players who have played well but
also they do not punish the players who
have played poorly they give back to the
players who have lost in this tone
players lose for many different reasons
mostly because they have not received
enough care they have not been loved
enough they have not received the right
kind of love which they need at the end
of the turn the monarch gives love to
the losers those I'll say go and sleep
on the streets does not say I'll lock
you up I'll take away your freedom
because you made a mistake no a monarch
loves and accepts the mistakes of the
divine children and helps them prepare
to the best of their capabilities for
the next term
that feels almost like four
yes
so this is this is not clear something
along the lines of there's a religious
dimension to this in the traditional
sense of religion in the manake could it
could also be conceived of as man's
relationship with God that God is these
enjoy that man is the an ark God is the
monarch and the right relationship
between man and God consists of this
written reciprocity where man gives what
he can of this world to God and God in
return makes sure that the earth remains
bountiful for man something something
like that the but the idea of being able
to include traditional religious
doctrine within this framework feels
quite appealing